<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Silvio blog</title>
    <link>https://example.com</link>
    <description>Silvio blog - Blog</description>
    <generator>Zine -- https://zine-ssg.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 22:34:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
      <item>
        <title>custom comments in neovim</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In neovim I use a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/folke/todo-comments.nvim&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;todo comment plugin&lt;/a&gt; which formats certain comments in your code. The plugin came with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nvim-lua/kickstart.nvim/tree/master&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;kickstart.nvim&lt;/a&gt; You can also define your own custom comments along with the color that should be used for highlighting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wanted to show a few ideas of custom comments I added. I know this may not be super interesting, but I like decorating my code to make me understand it better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://example.com/blog/custom comments in neovim/screenshot_todo_section.png&quot; width=&quot;800&quot;&gt; The Section comment is used in longer lists to seperate groups. In this example I define the properties of all the sound effects in the game and using the SELECTION: comment I can visually seperate them. By seraching for ‘SECTION: + some group name’ I can also quickly navigate to that code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the next example I created a STEP comment: &lt;img src=&quot;https://example.com/blog/custom comments in neovim/screenshot_step.png&quot; width=&quot;800&quot;&gt; I use this to divide longer algorithms into steps with a little description what each step does. This helps me to understand roughly what is going on in a function or algorithm, even when visiting the code after a few months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also added a very simple ADD comment: &lt;img src=&quot;https://example.com/blog/custom comments in neovim/screenshot_add.png&quot; width=&quot;800&quot;&gt; The TODO comment was already available but most of my TODO comments would start with ‘add xy’, so I thought, why not make a ADD comment with a nicer color. So I still use both TODO and ADD but for different scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <link>https://example.com/blog/custom comments in neovim/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 02:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://example.com/blog/custom comments in neovim/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
